Extending Python
扩展Python


Chapter Topics
本章主题
	Introduction/Motivation
    引言/动机
	Extending Python
    扩展Python
	Create Application Code
    创建应用程序代码
	Wrap Code in Boilerplate
    用样板包装你的代码
	Compile
    编译
	Import and Test
    导入并测试
	Reference Counting
    引用计数
	Threading and the GIL
    线程和GIL
	Related Topics
    相关话题
	
22
in this chapter, we will discuss how to take code written externally and
integrate that functionality into the Python programming environment.
We will first give you motivation for doing this, then take you through the
step-by-step process on how to do it. We should point out, though, that because
extensions are primarily done in the C language, all of the example code you
will see in this section is pure C but is easily portable to C++.
在本章中，我们将讨论如何编写扩展代码并将它们的功能整合到Python编程环境中来。
首先我们会给出这样做的原因，然后一步步地教您如何做。应当指出的是，虽然
大部分Python的扩展都是用C语言写的，并且下面的所有样例代码也都是由纯C语言写的，
但请放心，这些代码很容易就可以移植到C++中。


22.1  Introduction/Motivation
介绍/动机
22.1.1 What Are Extensions?
什么是扩展

In general, any code that you write that can be integrated or imported into
another Python script can be considered an extension. This new code can be
written in pure Python or in a compiled language like C and C++ (or Java for
Jython and C# or VisualBasic.NET for IronPython).
一般来说，所有能被整合或导入到其它python脚本的代码，都可以被称为扩展。
您可以用纯Python来写扩展，也可以用C和C++之类的编译型的语言来写扩展(或者也
可以用Java给Jython写扩展，也可以用C#或Visual Basic.NET给IronPython写扩展)。

One great feature of Python is that its extensions interact with the inter-
preter in exactly the same way as the regular Python modules. Python was
designed so that the abstraction of module import hides the underlying
implementation details from the code that uses such extensions. Unless the
client programmer searches the file system, he or she simply cannot tell
whether a module is written in Python or in a compiled language.
Python的一大特点就是，扩展和解释器之间的交互方式与普通的Python模块完全一样。
Python在设计之初就考虑到要让模块的导入机制足够抽象。抽象到让使用模块的代码
无法了解到模块的具体实现细节。除非那个程序员在磁盘中搜索这个模块文件，
否则，他/她就连这个模块到底是用Python写的，还是用某种编译语言写的都分辨不了。 


CORE NOTE: Creating extensions on different platforms
核心笔记：在不同平台上创建扩展

We will note here that extensions are generally available in a development
environment where you compile your own Python interpreter. There is a subtle
relationship between manual compilation versus obtaining the binaries. Although
compilation may be a bit trickier than just downloading and installing
binaries, you have the most flexibility in customizing the version of Python
you are using. If you intend to create extensions, you should perform this task
in a similar environment. The examples in this chapter are built on a
Unix-based system (which usually comes with a compilers), but, assuming you do
have access to a C/C++ (or Java) compiler and a Python development environment
in C/C++ (or Java), the only differences are in your compilation method.The
actual code to make your extensions usable in the Python world is the same on
any platform. If you are developing on a Win32 platform, you will need Visual
C++ “Developer Studio.” The Python distribution comes with project files for
version 7.1, but you may use older versions of VC++. More information on
building extensions on Win32 can be found at:
我们要注意的是，如果你曾自己编译过Python解释器，那么，在这样的环境中，扩展一般
都是可以使用的。自己手动编译扩展，和获取扩展的二进制文件是有一些不一样的。
虽然自己编译比简单的下载安装复杂一些，但由此得来的好处就是，你可以自由选择你想
使用的Python的版本。

虽然本章中的例子都是在Unix系统中开发的(一般的unix中，都自带编译器)。但只要你能
使用C/C++(或Java)的编译器并且C/C++(或Java)中有Python的开发环境。那唯一的区别只
是怎样来编译而已。无论在哪一个平台上，真正起作用的代码都是一样的。如果你在Win32
平台上进行开发，你需要有Visual C++开发环境。Python的发布包中自带了7.1版本的项目
文件。当然，你也可以使用老版本的VC。

想了解更多的关于如何在Win32上开发扩展的信息，你可以访问如下网页：

http://docs.python.org/ext/building-on-windows.html

Caution: Although we know enough not to move binaries between different hosts,
it is also a good idea just to compile on the same box and not move extensions
between boxes either, even if they are of the same architecture. Sometimes
slight differences of compiler or CPU will cause code not to work consistently.
警告：就算是相同的架构的两台电脑之间最好也不要互相共享二进制文件。最好是在各自的
电脑上编译Python和扩展。因为，有时就算是编译器或是CPU之间的些许差异，也会导致代码
不能正常工作。

22.1.2 Why Extend Python?
为什么要扩展Python？

Throughout the brief history of software engineering, programming languages
have always been taken at face value. What you see is what you get; it was
impossible to add new functionality to an existing language. In today’s pro-
gramming environment, however, the ability to customize one’s programming
environment is now a desired feature; it also promotes code reuse. Languages
such as TCL and Python are among the first languages to provide the ability to
extend the base language. So why would you want to extend a language like
Python, which is already feature-rich? There are several good reasons:
纵观软件工程的历史，编程语言都不具备可扩展性，你只能使用已有的功能，而不能为
语言增加新功能。现如今的编程环境中，可定制性也是一个很大的卖点。它可以促进代
码的复用。TCL和Python等语言是第一批提供可扩展性的语言。那么，为什么我们会想要
扩展像Python这种已经很完善的语言呢？有以下几点好理由：

Added/extra (non-Python) functionality
添加/额外的（非Python）功能

One reason for extending Python is the need to have new functionality not
provided by the core part of the language. This can be accomplished in either
pure Python or as a compiled extension, but there are certain things such as
creating new data types or embedding Python in an existing application which
must be compiled.
扩展Python的一个原因就是出于对一些新功能的需要，而Python语言的核心部分并没有提供这些功能。
这时，通过纯Python代码或者编译扩展都可以做到。但是有些情况，比如创建新的数据类型或者将
Python嵌入到其它已经存在的应用程序中，则必须得编译。


Bottleneck performance improvement
性能瓶颈的效率提升

It is well known that interpreted languages do not perform as fast as compiled
languages due to the fact that translation must happen on the fly and during
runtime. In general, moving a body of code into an extension will improve
overall performance. The problem is that it is sometimes not advantageous if
the cost is high in terms of resources.  
众所周知，由于解释型的语言是在运行时动态的翻译解释代码，这导致其运行速度比编译
型的语言慢。一般说来，把所有代码都放到扩展中，可以提升软件的整体性能。但有时，
由于时间与精力有限，这样做并不划算。

Percentage-wise, it is a wiser bet to do some simple profiling of the code to
identify what the bottlenecks are, and move those pieces of code out to an
extension. The gain can be seen more quickly and without expending as much in
terms of resources.
通常，先做一个简单的代码性能测试，看看瓶颈在哪里，然后把瓶颈部分在扩展中实现会是
一个比较简单有效的做法。效果立竿见影不说，而且还不用花费太多的时间与精力。

Keep proprietary source code private
保持专有源代码私密

Another important reason to create extensions is due to one side effect of
having a scripting language. For all the ease-of-use such languages bring to
the table, there really is no privacy as far as source code is concerned
because the executable is the source code.
创建扩展的另一个很重要的原因是脚本语言都有一个共同的缺陷，那就是所有的脚本语言
执行的都是源代码，这样一来源代码的保密性便无从谈起了。

Code that is moved out of Python and into a compiled language helps keep
proprietary code private because you ship a binary object. Because these
objects are compiled, they are not as easily reverse-engineered; thus, the
source remains more private. This is key when it involves special algorithms,
encryption or software security, etc.
把一部分代码从Python转到编译语言就可以保持专有源代码私密。因为，你只要发布二
进制文件就可以了。编译后的文件相对来说，更不容易被反向工程出来。因此，代码
能实现保密。尤其是涉及到特殊的算法，加密方法以及软件安全的时候，这样做就显得
非常至关重要了。

Another alternative to keeping code private is to ship pre-compiled .pyc files
only. It serves as a good middle ground between releasing the actual source
(.py files) and having to migrate that code to extensions.
另一种对代码保密的方法是只发布预编译后的.pyc文件。这是介于发布源代码(.py文件)
和把代码移植到扩展这两种方法之间的一种较好的折中的方法。

22.2  Extending Python by Writing Extensions
创建Python扩展

Creating extensions for Python involves three main steps:
为Python创建扩展需要三个主要的步骤：

1. Creating application code
2. Wrapping code with boilerplates
3. Compilation and testing

1. 创建应用程序代码
2. 利用样板来包装代码
3. 编译与测试

In this section, we will break out all three pieces and expose them all to you.
在这一节中，我们会将这三步逐一介绍给大家。

22.2.1 Create Your Application Code
创建您的应用程序代码

First, before any code becomes an extension, create a standalone “library.” In
other words, create your code keeping in mind that it is going to turn into a
Python module. Design your functions and objects with the vision that Python
code will be communicating and sharing data with your C code and vice versa.
首先，我们要建立的是一个“库”，要记住，我们要建立的是将在Python内运行的一个模块。
所以在设计你所需要的函数与对象的时候要注意到，你的C代码要能够很好的与Python的代码
进行双向的交互和数据共享。

Next, create test code to bulletproof your software. You may even use the
“Pythonic” development method of designating your main() function in C as the
testing application so that if your code is compiled, linked, and loaded into
an executable (as opposed to just a shared object), invocation of such an
executable will result in a regression test of your software library.
然后，写一些测试代码来保障你的代码的正确性。你可以在C代码中放一个main()函数，
使得你的代码可以被编译并链接成一个可执行文件(而不是一个动态库)，当你运行这个
可执行文件时，程序可以对你的软件库进行回归测试。这种是一种很符合Python风格的
做法。

For our extension example below, this is exactly what we do. The test case
involves two C functions that we want to bring to the world of Python
programming. The first is the recursive factorial function, fac(). The second,
reverse(), is a simple string reverse algorithm, whose main purpose is to
reverse a string “in place,” that is, to return a string whose characters are
all reversed from their original positions, all without allocating a separate
string to copy in reverse order. Because this involves the use of pointers, we
need to carefully design and debug our code before bringing Python into the
picture.
在下面的例子中，我们就将采用这种做法。测试用例分别针对我们想要导出到Python世界的
两个函数。一个是递归求阶乘的函数fac()。另一个reverse()函数实现了一个简单的字符串
反转算法，其主要目的是修改传入的字符串，使其内容完全反转，但不需要申请内存
后反着复制的方法。由于涉及到指针的使用，我们务必要在设计和调试时小心谨慎，以防
把问题带入Python。

Our first version, Extest1.c, is presented in Example 22.1.
Example 22.1中所列出的Extest1.c是我们的第一个版本。

This code consists of a pair of functions, fac() and reverse(), which are
implementations of the functionality we described above. fac() takes a single
integer argument and recursively calculates the result, which is eventually
returned to the caller once it exits the outermost call.
代码中，包含了两个函数fac()和reverse()。分别实现了我们刚刚所说的两个功能。
fac()接受一个整数参数并递归计算结果，在退出最后一层调用后最终返回到调用代码中。

The last piece of code is the required main() function. We use it to be our
tester, sending various arguments to fac() and reverse(). With this function,
we can actual tell whether our code works (or not).
最后一段代码是必要的main()函数。我们在这里面写测试代码，传不同的参数给fac()
和reverse()。有了这个函数，我们就可以了解我们的代码是否能得到正确的结果。

Now we should compile the code. For many versions of Unix with the gcc
compiler, we can use the following command:
现在，我们就可以编译这段代码了。在大部分有gcc编译器的unix系统中，我们都可以用
以下指令进行编译：

$ gcc Extest1.c -o Extest
$

To run our program, we issue the following command and get the output:
我们可以输入以下命令来运行我们的程序，并得到如下输出：

$ Extest
4! == 24
8! == 40320
12! == 479001600
reversing 'abcdef', we get 'fedcba'
reversing 'madam', we get 'madam'
$
Example 22.1 Pure C Version of Library (Extest1.c)

The following code represents our library of C functions which we want to wrap
so that we can use this code from within the Python interpreter. main() is our
tester function.
下面列出了我们想要包装并在Python解释器中使用的c函数的代码,main()是测试函数

5	int fac(int n)
6	{
7	if (n < 2) return(1); /* 0! == 1! == 1 */
8	return (n)*fac(n-1); /* n! == n*(n-1)! */
9	}
10


13	register char t,	/* 中间变量t */
14	*p = s,	/* fwd */
15	*q = (s + (strlen(s)-1));	/* bwd */
16
17	while (p < q)	/* if p < q */
18	{	/* swap & mv ptrs */
19	t = *p;
20	*p++ = *q;
21	*q-- = t;
22	}
23	return s;
24   }
25
26   int main()
27   {
28	char s[BUFSIZ];
29	printf("4! == %d\n", fac(4));
30	printf("8! == %d\n", fac(8));
31	printf("12! == %d\n", fac(12));
32	strcpy(s, "abcdef");
33	printf("reversing 'abcdef', we get '%s'\n", \
34	reverse(s));
35	strcpy(s, "madam");
36	printf("reversing 'madam', we get '%s'\n", \
37	reverse(s));
38	return 0;
39   }


We stress again that you should try to complete your code as much as possible,
because you do not want to mix debugging of your library with potential bugs
when integrating with Python. In other words, keep the debugging of your core
code separate from the debugging of the integration. The closer you write your
code to Python interfaces, the sooner your code will be integrated and work
correctly.
我们要再强调一次，你应该尽可能的完善你的代码。因为，在把代码集成到Python中后
再来调试你的核心代码，查找潜在的bug是件很痛苦的事情。也就是说，调试核心
代码与调试集成这两件事应该分开来做。要知道，与Python的接口代码写得越完善，
集成的正确性就越容易保证。

Each of our functions takes a single value and returns a single value. It’s
pretty cut and dried, so there shouldn’t be a problem integrating with Python.
Note that, so far, we have not seen any connection or relationship with Python.
We are simply creating a standard C or C++ application.
我们的两个函数都只接受一个参数，并返回一个值。这是很标准的情况，与Python集成的
时候应该不会有什么问题。注意，到现在为止，我们所做的都还与Python没什么关系。
我们只是简单地创建了一个C/C++的应用程序而已。


22.2.2  Wrap Your Code in Boilerplate
用样板来包装你的代码

The entire implementation of an extension primarily revolves around the
“wrapping” concept that we introduced earlier in Section 13.15.1. You should
design your code in such a way that there is a smooth transition between the
world of Python and your implementing language. This interfacing code is
commonly called “boilerplate” code because it is a necessity if your code is to
talk to the Python interpreter.
整个扩展的实现都是围绕着13.15.1节所说的“包装”这个概念进行的。你的设计要尽可能让
你的实现语言与Python无缝结合。接口的代码被称为“样板”代码，它是你的代码与Python
解释器之间进行交互所必不可少的一部分。

There are four main pieces to the boilerplate software:
我们的样板主要分为4步：

1. Include Python header file
2. Add PyObject* Module_func() Python wrappers for each module function
3. Add PyMethodDef ModuleMethods[] array/table for each module function
4. Add void initModule() module initializer function

1. 包含Python的头文件。
2. 为每个模块的每一个函数增加一个型如PyObject* Module_func()的包装函数。
3. 为每个模块增加一个型如PyMethodDef ModuleMethods[]的数组。
4. 增加模块初始化函数void initModule()


Include Python Header File
包含Python头文件

The first thing you should do is to find your Python include files and make
sure your compiler has access to that directory. On most Unix-based systems,
this would be either /usr/local/include/python2.x or /usr/include/python2.x,
where the “2.x” is your version of Python. If you compiled and installed your
Python interpreter, you should not have a problem because the system generally
knows where your files are installed. 　Add the inclusion of the Python.h
header file to your source. The line will look something like:
首先，你要找到Python的头文件在哪，并且确保你的编译器有权限访问它们。在大多数
类Unix的系统里，它们都会在/usr/local/include/python2.x或/usr/include/python2.x
目录中。其中，"2.x"是你所使用的Python的版本号。如果你曾编译并安装过Python解释器，
那应该不会碰到什么问题，因为这时，系统一般都会知道你的文件安装在哪。像下面这样在
你的代码里加入一行：

#include "Python.h"

That is the easy part. Now you have to add the rest of the boilerplate
software.
这部分比较简单。接下来再看看怎么在样板中加入其它的部分。

Add PyObject* Module_func() Python
Wrappers for Each Function
为每个模块的每一个函数增加一个型如PyObject* Module_func()的包装函数。

This part is the trickiest. For each function you want accessible to the Python
environment, you will create a static PyObject* function with the module name
along with an underscore ( _ ) prepended to it.
这一部分最需要技巧。你需要为所有想被Python环境访问的函数都增加一个静态的函数，
函数的返回值类型为PyObject*，函数名前面要加上模块名和一个下划线(_)。

For example, we want fac() to  be one of the functions available for import
from Python and we will use Extest as the name of our final module,
so we create a “wrapper” called Extest_fac(). In the client Python script,
there  will  be  an  “import Extest”  and  an  “Extest.fac()”  call  some-
where (or just “fac()” for “from Extest import fac”).
比方说，我们希望在Python中，能够import我们的fac()函数，其所在的模块名为Extest
那么，我们就要创建一个包装函数叫Extest_fac()。在使用这个函数的Python脚本中，
使用方法是先"import Extest"然后调用"Extest.fac()"(或者先"from Extest import fac"，
然后直接调用"fac()")

The job of the wrapper is to take Python values, convert them to C, then make a
call to the appropriate function with what we want. When our function has
completed, and it is time to return to the world of Python, it is also the job
of this wrapper to take whatever return values we designate, convert them to
Python, and then perform the return, passing back any values as necessary.
包装函数的用处就是先把Python的值传递给C，然后调用我们想要调用的相关函数。当这个
函数完成要返回Python的时候，把函数的计算结果转换成Python的对象，然后返回给Python。

In the case of fac(), when the client program invokes Extest.fac(), our wrapper
will be called. We will accept a Python integer, convert it to a C integer,
call our C function fac() and obtain another integer result. We then have to
take that return value, convert it back to a Python integer, then return from
the call. (In your head, try to keep in mind that you are writing the code that
will proxy for a “def fac(n)” declaration. When you are returning, it is as if
that imaginary Python fac() function is completing.)
对于fac()函数来说，当客户程序调用Extest.fac()的时候，我们的包装函数就会被调用。
它接受一个Python的整数参数，把它转为C的整数，然后调用C的fac()函数，得到一个整型
的返回值，最后把这个返回值转为Python的整型数做为整个函数调用的结果返回回去。
(在你头脑中，要保持一个想法：我们所写的其实就是"def fac(n)"这段声明的一个代理函数,
当代理函数返回的时候，就像是这个想像中的Python的fac()函数在返回一样。)

So, you’re asking, how does this conversion take place? The answer is with the
PyArg_Parse*() functions when going from Python to C, and Py_BuildValue()
when returning from C to Python. 
那么，你就会问了，怎样才能完成这样的转换呢？答案是，在从Python到C的转换就用
PyArg_Parse*系列函数。在从C转到Python的时候，就用Py_BuildValue()函数

The PyArg_Parse*() functions are similar to the C sscanf() function. It takes
a stream of bytes, and, according to some format string, parcels them off to
corresponding container variables, which, as expected, take pointer addresses.
They both return 1 on successful parsing and 0 otherwise. 
PyArg_Parse系列函数的用法跟C的sscanf函数很像，都接受一个字符串流，并根据一个
指定的格式字符串进行解析，把结果放入到相应的指针所指的变量中去。它们的返回值为1
表示解析成功，返回值为0表示失败。

Py_BuildValue() works like sprintf(), taking a format string and converting all
arguments to a single returned object containing those values in the formats
that you requested.
Py_BuildValue的用法跟sprintf很像，把所有的参数按格式字符串所指定的格式转换成一个
Python的对象。

You will find a summary of these functions in Table 22.1.
表22.1罗列了这些函数的概要。

A set of conversion codes is used to convert data objects between C and
Python; they are given in Table 22.2.
表22.2所列出的转换代码用于在C与Python之间做数据的转换。


These conversion codes are the ones given in the respective format strings that
dictate how the values should be converted when moving between both languages.
Note: The conversion types are different for Java since all data types are
classes. Consult the Jython documentation to obtain the corresponding Java
types for Python objects. The same applies for C# and VB.NET.
这些转换代码出现在格式字符串当中，用于指定各个值的数据类型，以便于在两种
语言之间做转换。注：由于Java的所有数据类型都是类，所以Java的转换类型不一样。
Python对象在Java中所对应的数据类型请参考Jython的相关文档。C#也有同样的问题。

Table 22.1 Converting Data Between Python and C/C++
表22.1 Python和C/C++之间的数据转换

Function	Description



       Python to C

int
PyArg_ParseTuple()

int
PyArg_ParseTupleAndKeywords()


Converts (a tuple of) arguments passed from Python to C
把Python传过来的参数转为C

Same as PyArg_ParseTuple()
but also parses keyword arguments
与PyArg_ParseTuple()作用相同，但是同时解析关键字参数


C to Python

PyObject* Py_BuildValue()


Converts C data values into a Python return object, either a single object or a single tuple of objects
把C的数据转为Python的一个对象或一组对象，然后返回之。





Table 22.2  Common Codes to Convert Data Between Python
and C/C++


Format Code

Python Type

C/C++ Type

s

str

char*

z

str/None

char*/NULL

i

int

int

l

long

long

c

str

char

d

float

double

D

complex

Py_Complex*

O

(any)

PyObject*

S

str

PyStringObject
Here we show you our completed Extest_fac() wrapper function:

static PyObject *
Extest_fac(PyObject *self, PyObject *args) {

int res;	// parse result 
int num;	// arg for fac() PyObject* retval;	// return value

res = PyArg_ParseTuple(args, "i", &num);
if (!res) {	// TypeError
return NULL;
}
res = fac(num);
retval = (PyObject*)Py_BuildValue("i", res);
return retval;
}

The first step is to parse the data received from Python. It should be a reg-
ular integer, so we use the “i” conversion code to indicate as such. If the
value was indeed an integer, then it gets stored in the num variable.
Otherwise, PyArg_ParseTuple() will return a NULL, in which case we also return
one. In our case, it will generate a TypeError exception that tells the client
user that we are expecting an integer.
首先，我们要解析Python传过来的数据。例子中，我们使用格式字符串"i"，表示我们期望
得到一个整型的变量。如果传进来的的确是一个整型的变量，那就把它保存到num变量中。
否则，PyArg_ParseTuple()会返回NULL，同时，我们的函数也返回一个NULL。这时，就会
产生一个TypeError异常，通知客户我们期望传入一个整型变量。

We then call fac() with the value stored in num and put the result in res,
reusing that variable. Now we build our return object, a Python integer, again
using a conversion code of “i.” Py_BuildValue() creates an integer Python
object which we then return. That’s all there is to it!
然后，我们会调用fac()函数，其参数为num，把返回结果放在res变量中。
最后，通过调用Py_BuildValue()函数，格式字符串为"i"，把结果转为Python的整数类型并返回。
这样，我们就完成了整个调用过程。

In fact, once you have created wrapper after wrapper, you tend to shorten your
code somewhat to avoid extraneous use of variables. Try to keep your code
legible, though. We take our Extest_fac() function and reduce it to its smaller
version given here, using only one variable, num:
事实上，包装函数写得多了之后，你会慢慢的把代码写得越来越短，以减少中间变量的使用，
同时也会增加代码的可读性。我们以Extest_fac()函数为例，把它改写得短小一些，只使用
一个变量num：

static PyObject *
Extest_fac(PyObject *self, PyObject *args) {
int num;
if (!PyArg_ParseTuple(args, "i", &num))
return NULL;
return (PyObject*)Py_BuildValue("i", fac(num));
}

What about reverse()? Well, since you already know how to return a single
value, we are going to change our reverse() example somewhat, returning two
values instead of one. We will return a pair of strings as a tuple, the first
element being the string as passed in to us, and the second being the newly
reversed string.
那么reverse怎么实现呢？既然你已经知道怎么返回一个值了，那我们把reverse()的需求
稍微改一下，变成返回两个值。我们将返回一个包含两个字符串的tuple。第一个值是传
进来的字符串，第二个值是反转后的字符串。

To show you that there is some flexibility, we will call this function
Extest.doppel() to indicate that its behavior differs from reverse(). Wrapping
our code into an Extest_doppel() function, we get:
我们将把这个函数命名为Extest.doppel()，以示与reverse()函数的区别。把代码包装到
Extest_doppel()函数后，我们得到如下代码：

static PyObject *
Extest_doppel(PyObject *self, PyObject *args) {
char *orig_str;
if (!PyArg_ParseTuple(args, "s", &orig_str)) return NULL;
return (PyObject*)Py_BuildValue("ss", orig_str, \
reverse(strdup(orig_str)));
}

As in Extest_fac(), we take a single input value, this time a string, and store
it into orig_str. Notice that we use the “s” conversion code now. We then call
strdup() to create a copy of the string. (Since we want to return the original
one as well, we need a string to reverse, so the best candidate is just a copy
of the string.) strdup() creates and returns a copy, which we immediate
dispatch to reverse(). We get back a reversed string.
跟Extest_fac()类似，我们接收一个字符串型的参数，保存到orig_str中。注意，这次，
我们要使用"s"格式字符串。然后调用strdup()函数把这个字符串复制一份(由于我们
要同时返回原始字符串和反转后的字符串，所以我们需要复制一份)。把新复制的字符串
传给reverse函数，我们就得到了反转后的字符串。

As you can see, Py_BuildValue() puts together both strings using a conversion
string of “ss.” This creates a tuple of two strings, the original string and
the reversed one. End of story, right? Unfortunately, no.
如你所见，我们用"ss"格式字符串让Py_BuildValue()函数生成了一个含有两个字符串的
tuple，分别放了原始字符串和反转后的字符串。这样就完成所有的工作了吗？很不幸，还没。

We got caught by one of the perils of C programming: the memory leak, that is,
when memory is allocated but not freed. Memory leaks are analogous to bor-
rowing books from the library but not returning them. You should always release
resources that you have acquired when you no longer require them. How did we
commit such a crime with our code (which looks innocent enough)?
我们碰到了C语言的一个陷阱：内存泄露。即内存被申请了，但没有被释放。就像去图书馆
借了书，但是没有还一样。无论何时，你都应该释放所有你申请的，不再需要的内存。
看！我们写的代码犯了多大的罪过啊。(虽然看上去好像很无辜的样子)

When Py_BuildValue() puts together the Python object to return, it makes copies
of the data it has been passed. In our case here, that would be a pair of
strings. The problem is that we allocated the memory for the second string,
but we did not release that memory when we finished, leaking it. What we really
want to do is to build the return object and then free the memory that we
allocated in our wrapper. We have no choice but to lengthen our code to:
Py_BuildValue()函数生成要返回的Python对象的时候，会把转入的数据复制一份。上例中，
那两个字符串就会被复制出来。问题就在于，我们申请了用于存放第二个字符串的内存，
但是，在退出的时候没有释放它。于是，这片内存就泄露了。正确的做法是：先生成要返回
的对象，然后释放在包装函数中申请的内存。我们必需要这样这样修改我们的代码：

static PyObject *
Extest_doppel(PyObject *self, PyObject *args) {
    char *orig_str; // 原始字符串
    char *dupe_str; // 反转后的字符串 
    PyObject* retval;
    if (!PyArg_ParseTuple(args, "s", &orig_str)) 
        return NULL;
        
    retval = (PyObject*)Py_BuildValue("ss", orig_str, \
                    dupe_str=reverse(strdup(orig_str)));
    free(dupe_str);
    return retval;
}

We introduce the dupe_str variable to point to the newly allocated string and
build the return object. Then we free() the memory allocated and finally return
back to the caller. Now we are done.
我们用dupe_str变量指向了新申请的字符串，并依此生成了要返回的对象。然后，我们调用
free()函数释放这个字符串，最后，返回到调用程序。终于，完成了我们要做的事情。


Add PyMethodDef ModuleMethods[]
Array/Table for Each Module Function
为每个模块增加一个型如PyMethodDef ModuleMethods[]的数组。

Now that both of our wrappers are complete, we want to list them somewhere so
that the Python interpreter knows how to import and access them. This is the
job of the ModuleMethods[] array.
现在，我们已经完成了两个包装函数。我们需要把它们列在某个地方，以便于Python解释
器能够导入并调用它们。这就是ModuleMethods[]数组要做的事情。

It is made up of an array of arrays, with each individual array containing
information about each function, terminated by a NULL array marking the end of
the list. For our Extest module, we create the following ExtestMethods[]
array:
这个数组由多个数组组成。其中的每一个数组都包含了一个函数的信息。最后放一个NULL
数组表示列表的结束。我们为Extest模块创建一个ExtestMethods[]数组：

static PyMethodDef
ExtestMethods[] = {
{ "fac", Extest_fac, METH_VARARGS },
{ "doppel", Extest_doppel, METH_VARARGS },
{ NULL, NULL },
};

The Python-accessible names are given, followed by the corresponding wrapping
functions. The constant METH_VARARGS is given, indicating a set of arguments in
the form of a tuple. If we are using PyArg_ParseTupleAndKeywords() with
keyworded arguments, we would logically OR this flag with the METH_KEYWORDS
constant. Finally, a pair of NULLs properly terminates our list of two
functions.
每一个数组都包含了函数在Python中的名字，相应的包装函数的名字以及一个METH_VARARGS常量。
其中，METH_VARARGS常量表示参数以tuple形式传入。如果我们要使用
PyArg_ParseTupleAndKeywords()函数来分析命名参数的话，我们还需要让这个标志常量与METH_KEYWORDS常量进行逻辑与运算
常量。最后，用两个NULL来结束我们的函数信息列表。


Add void initModule() Module
Initializer Function
增加模块初始化函数void initModule()

The final piece to our puzzle is the module initializer function. This code is
called when our module is imported for use by the interpreter. In this code, we
make one call to Py_InitModule() along with the module name and the name of the
ModuleMethods[] array so that the interpreter can access our module functions.
For our Extest module, our initExtest() procedure looks like this:
所有工作的最后一部分就是模块的初始化函数。这部分代码在模块被导入的时候被解释器
调用。在这段代码中，我们需要调用Py_InitModule()函数，并把模块名和ModuleMethods[]
数组的名字传递进去，以便于解释器能正确的调用我们模块中的函数。
对Extest模块来说，initExtest()函数应该是这个样子的：

void initExtest() {
    Py_InitModule("Extest", ExtestMethods);
}

We are now done with all our wrapping. We add all this code to our original
code from Extest1.c and merge the results into a new file called Extest2.c,
concluding the development phase of our example.
这样，所有的包装都已经完成了。我们把以上代码与之前的Extest1.c合并到一个
新文件Extest2.c中。到此为止，我们的开发阶段就已经结束了。

Another approach to creating an extension would be to make your wrapping code
first, using “stubs” or test or dummy functions which will, during the course
of development, be replaced by the fully functional pieces of implemented code.
That way you can ensure that your interface between Python and C is correct,
and then use Python to test your C code.
创建扩展的另一种方法是先写包装代码，使用桩函数，测试函数或哑函数。在开发过程中
慢慢的把这些函数用有实际功能的函数替换。这样，你可以确保Python和C之间的接口
函数是正确的，并用它们来测试你的C代码。

22.2.2 Compilation
编译

Now we are on to the compilation phase. In order to get your new wrapper Python
extension to build, you need to get it to compile with the Python library. This
task has been standardized (since 30) across platforms to make life a lot
easier for extension writers. The distutils package is used to build, install,
and distribute modules, extensions, and packages. It came about back in Python
2.0 and replaced the old 1.x way of building extensions using “makefiles.”
Using distutils, we can follow this easy recipe:
现在，我们已经到了编译阶段。为了让你的新Python扩展能被创建，你需要把它们与Python
库放在一起编译。现在已经有了一套跨30多个平台的规范，它极大的方便了编写扩展的人。
distutils包被用来编译，安装和分发这些模块，扩展和包。这个模块在Python2.0的时候就
已经出现了，并用于代替1.x版本时的用Makefile来编译扩展的方法。使用distutils包的时候
我们可以方便的按以下步骤来做：

1. Create setup.py
2. Compile and link your code by running setup.py
3. Import your module from Python
4. Test function

1. 创建 setup.py
2. 通过运行setup.py来编译和连接您的代码
3. 从Python中导入您的模块
4. 测试功能

Create setup.py
创建setup.py

The next step is to create a setup.py file. The bulk of the work will be done
by the setup() function. All the lines of code that come before that call are
preparatory steps. For building extension modules, you need to create an
Extension instance per extension. Since we only have one, we only need one
Extension instance:
下一步就是要创建一个setup.py文件。编译最主要的工作由setup()函数来完成。在这个函数调用
之前的所有代码，都是一些预备动作。为了能编译扩展，你要为每一个扩展创建一个
Extension实例，在这里，我们只有一个扩展，所以只要创建一个Extension实例：

Extension('Extest', sources=['Extest2.c'])

The first argument is the (full) extension name, including any high-level
packages if necessary. The name should be in full dotted-attribute notation.
Ours is standalone, hence the name “Extest.” sources is a list of all the
source files. Again, we only have the one, Extest2.c.
第一个参数是（完整的）扩展的名字，如果模块是包的一部分的话，还要加上用'.'分隔的
完整的包的名字。我们这里的扩展是独立的，所以名字只要写"Extest"就好了。sources参数
是所有源代码的文件列表。同样，我们也只有一个文件：Extest2.c。

Now we are ready to call setup(). It takes a name argument for what it is
building and a list of the items to build. Since we are creating an extension,
we set it a list of extension modules to build as ext_modules. The syntax will
be like this:
现在，我们可以调用setup()了。setup需要两个参数:一个名字参数表示要编译哪个东西，一个列表列出要编译的对象。由于我们要编译的是一个扩展，我们把ext_modules
参数的值设为扩展模块的列表。语法如下：

setup('Extest', ext_modules=[...])

Example 22.2   The Build Script (setup.py)
例22.2 编译脚本(setup.py)

This script compiles our extension into the build/lib.* subdirectory.
这个脚本会把我们的扩展编译到build/lib.*子目录中。

1	#!/usr/bin/env python
2
3	from distutils.core import setup, Extension
4
5	MOD = 'Extest'
6	setup(name=MOD, ext_modules=[
7	Extension(MOD, sources=['Extest2.c'])])


Since we only have one module, we combine the instantiation of our extension
module into our call to setup(), setting the module name as “constant” MOD on
the preceding line:
由于我们只有一个模块。我们把我们扩展模块对象的实例化操作放到了setup()的调用代码
中。模块的名字我们就传预先定义的“常量”MOD：

MOD = 'Extest'
setup(name=MOD, ext_modules=[
        Extension(MOD, sources=['Extest2.c'])])

There are many more options to setup(), which are too numerous to list here.
You can find out more about creating setup.py and calling setup() in the
official Python documentation that we refer to at the end of this chapter.
Example 22.2 shows the complete script that we are using for our example.
setup()函数还有很多选项可以设置。限于篇幅，不能完全罗列。读者可以在本章最后
所列的官方文档中找到setup.py和setup()函数相关的信息。例22.2给出了我们例子所要
用的完整的脚本代码。


Compile and Link Your Code by Running setup.py
通过运行setup.py来编译和连接您的代码

Now that we have our setup.py file, we can build our extension by running it
with the “build” directive, as we have done here on our Mac (your output will
differ based on the version of the operating system you are running as well as
the version of Python you are using):
现在，我们已经有了setup.py文件。运行setup.py build命令就可以开始编译我们的扩展
了。在我们的Mac机上的输出如下（使用不同版本的Python或是不一样的操作系统时，输出
会有一些不同）：

$ python setup.py build running build
running build_ext
building 'Extest' extension creating build
creating build/temp.macosx-10.x-fat-2.x
gcc -fno-strict-aliasing -Wno-long-double -no-cpp-
precomp -mno-fused-madd -fno-common -dynamic -DNDEBUG -g
-I/usr/include -I/usr/local/include -I/sw/include -I/ usr/local/include/python2.x -c Extest2.c -o build/ temp.macosx-10.x-fat-2.x/Extest2.o
creating build/lib.macosx-10.x-fat-2.x
gcc -g -bundle -undefined dynamic_lookup -L/usr/lib -L/ usr/local/lib -L/sw/lib -I/usr/include -I/usr/local/ include -I/sw/include build/temp.macosx-10.x-fat-2.x/ Extest2.o -o build/lib.macosx-10.x-fat-2.x/Extest.so

22.2.3 Import and Test
导入和测试

Import Your Module from Python
从Python中导入您的模块

Your extension module will be created in the build/lib.* directory from where
you ran your setup.py script. You can either change to that directory to test
your module or install it into your Python distribution with:
你的扩展会被创建在你运行setup.py脚本所在目录下的build/lib.*目录中。你可以切换
到那个目录中来测试你的模块，或者也可以用以下命令把它安装到你的Python中：

$ python setup.py install

If you do install it, you will get the following output:
如果安装成功，你会看到：

running install running build running build_ext running install_lib
copying build/lib.macosx-10.x-fat-2.x/Extest.so ->
/usr/local/lib/python2.x/site-packages

Now we can test out our module from the interpreter:
现在，我们可以在解释器里测试我们的模块了：

>>> import Extest
>>> Extest.fac(5)
120
>>> Extest.fac(9)
362880
>>> Extest.doppel('abcdefgh')
('abcdefgh', 'hgfedcba')
>>> Extest.doppel("Madam, I'm Adam.")
("Madam, I'm Adam.", ".madA m'I ,madaM")


Test Function
测试功能

The one last thing we want to do is to add a test function. In fact, we already
have one, in the form of the main() function. Now, it is potentially danger-
ous to have a main() function in our code because there should only be one
main() in the system. We remove this danger by changing the name of our main()
to test() and wrapping it, adding Extest_test() and updating the ExtestMethods
array so that they both look like this:
我们想要做的最后一件是就是加上一个测试函数。事实上，我们已经写了一个了。就是那个
main()函数。现在，在我们代码中放一个main()函数是一件比较危险的事。因为，一个系统
中，只能有一个main()函数。我们把main()函数改名为test()，加个Extest_test()函数把
它包装起来，然后在ExtestMethods中加入这个函数就不会有这样的问题了。代码如下：

static PyObject *
Extest_test(PyObject *self, PyObject *args) {
    test();
    return (PyObject*)Py_BuildValue("");
}
static PyMethodDef
ExtestMethods[] = {
    { "fac", Extest_fac, METH_VARARGS },
    { "doppel", Extest_doppel, METH_VARARGS },
    { "test", Extest_test, METH_VARARGS },
    { NULL, NULL },
};

The Extest_test() module function just runs test() and returns an empty string,
resulting in a Python value of None being returned to the caller. Now we can
run the same test from Python:
Extest_test()模块函数只负责运行test()函数，并返回一个空字符串。Python的None作为
返回值，传给了调用者。现在，我们可以在Python中，调用同样的test()函数了：

>>> Extest.test()
4! == 24
8! == 40320
12! == 479001600
reversing 'abcdef', we get 'fedcba'
reversing 'madam', we get 'madam'
>>>

In Example 22.3, we present the final version of Extest2.c that was used to
generate the output we just witnessed.
在例22.3中，我们给出了Extest2.c的最终版本。这个版本会输出我们刚才所看到的结果。

In this example, we chose to segregate our C code from our Python code.
在本例中，我们把我们的C代码，和Python相关的代码分开放。一段在上面，一段在下面。

It just kept things easier to read and is no problem with our short example. In
practice, these source files tend to get large, and some choose to implement
their wrappers completely in a different source file, i.e., ExtestWrappers.c
or something of that nature.
这样可以让代码更具可读性。对于小程序来说，没有任何问题。但在实际应用中，源代码
会越写越大。一部分人就会考虑把他们的包装函数放在另一个源文件中。起个诸如
ExtestWrappers.c之类好记的名字。

22.2.5 Reference Counting
引用计数

You may recall that Python uses reference counting as a means of keeping track
of objects and deallocating objects no longer referenced as part of the garbage
collection mechanism. When creating extensions, you must pay extra special
attention to how you manipulate Python objects because you must be mindful of
whether or not you need to change the reference count for such objects. 
也许你还记得，Python使用引用计数作为跟踪一个对象是否不再被使用，所占内存是否应该
被回收的手段。它是垃圾回收机制的一部分。当创建扩展时，你必需对如何操作Python对象
要格外的小心。你时时刻刻都要注意是否要改变某个对象的引用计数。

There are two types of references you may have to an object, one of which is an
owned reference, meaning that the reference count to the object is incremented
by one to indicate your ownership. One place where you would definitely have an
owned reference is where you create a Python object from scratch.
一个对象可能有两类引用。一种是拥有引用，你要对这个对象的引用计数加1，以表示你也
拥有这个对象的所有权。如果这个Python对象是你自己创建的，那这时，你肯定拥有这个对
象的所有权。

When you are done with a Python object, you must dispose of your ownership,
either by decrementing the reference count, transferring your ownership by
passing it on, or storing the object. Failure to dispose of an owned reference
creates a memory leak.
当你不再需要一个Python对象时，你必须要交出你的所有权，要么把引用计数减1，要么把所有权交给别人，要么把这个对象存到其它的容器中(tuple, list等)。没有交出所有权就会导致内存泄露。



You may also have a borrowed reference to an object. Somewhat lower on the
responsibility ladder, this is where you are passed the reference of an object,
but otherwise do not manipulate the data in any way. Nor do you have to worry
about its reference count, as long as you do not hold on to this reference
after its reference count has decreased to zero. You may convert your borrowed
reference to an owned reference simply by incrementing an object’s reference
count.
你也可以拥有对象的借引用。相对来说，这种方式的责任就小一些。除非是别人在外面把对象
传递给你。否则，不要用任何方式修改对象里的数据。你也不用时刻考虑对象引用计数的问题，
只要你不会在对象的引用计数减为0之后再去使用这个对象。你也可以把借引用对象的引用的
数量加1，从而真正的引用这个对象。


Example 22.3  Python-Wrapped Version of C Library (Extest2.c)
例22.3 C库的Python包装版本(Extest2.c)


5	int fac(int n)
6	{
7		if (n < 2) return(1);
8		return (n)*fac(n-1);
9	}
10


13	register char t,
14	*p = s,
15	*q = (s + (strlen(s) - 1));
16
17	while (s && (p < q))
18	{
19		t = *p;
20		*p++ = *q;
21		*q-- = t;
22	}
23	return s;
24    }
25
26    int test()
27    {
28	char s[BUFSIZ];
29	printf("4! == %d\n", fac(4));
30	printf("8! == %d\n", fac(8));
31	printf("12! == %d\n", fac(12));
32	strcpy(s, "abcdef");
33	printf("reversing 'abcdef', we get '%s'\n", \
34	reverse(s));
35	strcpy(s, "madam");
36	printf("reversing 'madam', we get '%s'\n", \
37	reverse(s));
38	return 0;
39    }
40
41    #include "Python.h"
42
43    static PyObject *
44    Extest_fac(PyObject *self, PyObject *args)
45    {
46	int num;
47	if (!PyArg_ParseTuple(args, "i", &num))
48	return NULL;
49	return (PyObject*)Py_BuildValue("i", fac(num));}
50    }
51
52    static PyObject *
53    Extest_doppel(PyObject *self, PyObject *args)
54    {
55	char *orig_str;
56	char *dupe_str;
57	PyObject* retval;
58
59	if (!PyArg_ParseTuple(args, "s", &orig_str))
60	return NULL;
61	retval = (PyObject*)Py_BuildValue("ss", orig_str, \
62	dupe_str=reverse(strdup(orig_str)));
63	free(dupe_str);
64	return retval;
65    }
66
67    static PyObject *
68    Extest_test(PyObject *self, PyObject *args)
69    {
70	test();
71	return (PyObject*)Py_BuildValue("");
72    }
73
74    static PyMethodDef
75    ExtestMethods[] =
76    {
77	{ "fac", Extest_fac, METH_VARARGS },
78	{ "doppel", Extest_doppel, METH_VARARGS },
79	{ "test", Extest_test, METH_VARARGS },
80	{ NULL, NULL },
81    };
82
83    void initExtest()
84    {
85	Py_InitModule("Extest", ExtestMethods);
86    }


Python provides a pair of C macros which are used to change the reference
count to a Python object. They are given in Table 22.3.
Python提供了一对C的宏，可以用来改变Python对象的引用计数。见表22.3。

In our above Extest_test() function, we return None by building a PyObject with
an empty string; however, it can also be accomplished by becoming an owner of
the None object, PyNone, incrementing your reference count to it, and returning
it explicitly, as in the following alternative piece of code:
在上面的Extest_test()函数中，我们创建了一个空字符串的PyObject对象，用以返回None。
或者，你也可以对空对象(PyNone)的引用计数加1，成为PyNone的拥有者，然后直接返回
PyNone。见下例：


Table 22.3  Macros for Performing Python Object Reference Counting
表22.3 用于Python对象引用计数的宏

Function	Description
函数		说明

Py_INCREF(obj) 增加对象obj的引用计数
Py_DECREF(obj) 减少对象obj的引用计数


static PyObject *
Extest_test(PyObject *self, PyObject *args) {
	test(); Py_INCREF(Py_None); return PyNone;
}

Py_INCREF() and Py_DECREF() also have versions that check for NULL objects.
They are Py_XINCREF() and Py_XDECREF(), respectively.
Py_INCREF()和Py_DECREF()两个函数也有一个先检查对象是否为空的版本，分别为
Py_XINCREF()和Py_XDECREF()。

We strongly urge the reader to consult the Python documentation regarding
extending and embedding Python for all the details with regard to reference
counting (see the documentation reference in the Appendix).
我们强烈建议读者阅读Python文档的扩展和嵌入Python部分中关于引用计数的内容。
(见附录中的文档参考部分)


22.2.6 Threading and the GIL
线程和全局解释锁（GIL）

Extension writers must be aware that their code may be executed in a multi-
threaded Python environment. Back in Section 18.3.1, we introduced the Python
Virtual Machine (PVM) and the Global Interpreter Lock (GIL) and described how
only one thread of execution can be running at any given time in the PVM and
that the GIL is responsible for keeping other threads from running.
Furthermore, we indicated that code calling external functions such as in
extension code would keep the GIL locked until the call returns.
编译扩展的人必须要注意，他们的代码有可能会被运行在一个多线程的Python环境中。
早在18.3.1节，我们就介绍了Python虚拟机(PVM)和全局解释锁(GIL)。并描述了，在PVM
中，任何时候，同时只会有一个线程被运行。其它线程会被GIL停下来。而且，我们指出
调用扩展代码等外部函数时，代码会被GIL锁住，直到函数返回为止。

We also hinted that there was a remedy, a way for the extension programmer to
release the GIL, for example before performing a system call. This is
accomplished by “blocking” your code off to where threads may (and may not) run
safely using another pair of C macros, Py_BEGIN_ALLOW_THREADS and
Py_END_ALLOW_THREADS. A block of code bounded by these macros will permit other
threads to run.
前面，我们也提到过一种折衷方案，可以让编写扩展的程序员释放GIL，例如在系统调用前就可以做到。
这是通过将您的代码和线程隔离实现的，这些线程使用了另外的两个C宏Py_BEGIN_ALLOW_THREADS和Py_END_ALLOW_THREADS
保证了运行和非运行时的安全性。由这些宏包裹的代码将会允许其他线程的运行。

As with the reference counting macros, we urge you to consult with the
documentation regarding extending and embedding Python as well as the Python/C
API reference manual.
同引用计数宏一样，我们强烈建议你好好看看关于扩展和嵌入Python的文档以及Python/C API参考手册。

22.3 Related Topics
相关话题

SWIG

There is an external tool available called SWIG, which stands for Simplified
Wrapper and Interface Generator. It was written by David Beazley, also the
author of Python Essential Reference. It is a software tool that can take anno-
tated C/C++ header files and generate wrapped code, ready to compile for
Python, Tcl, and Perl. Using SWIG will free you from having to write the
boilerplate code we’ve seen in this chapter. You only need to worry about
coding the solution part of your project in C/C++. All you have to do is create
your files in the SWIG format, and it will do the background work on your
behalf. You can find out more information about SWIG from its main Web site
located at the following Web address (URL):
有一个外部工具叫SWIG，是Simplified Wrapper and Interface Generator的缩写。
其作者为David Beazley，同时也是Python Essential Referenc一书的作者。这个工具
可以根据特别注释过的C/C++头文件生成能给Python，Tcl和Perl使用的包装代码。使用
SWIG可以省去你写前面所说的样板代码的时间。你只要关心怎么用C/C++解决你的实际
问题就好了。你所要做的就是按SWIG的格式编写文件，其余的就都由SWIG来完成。你
可以通过下面的网址找到关于SWIG的更多信息。

http://swig.org


Pyrex

One obvious weakness of creating C/C++ extensions (raw or with SWIG) is that
you have to write C/C++ (surprise, surprise), with all of its strengths, and,
more importantly, its pitfalls. Pyrex gives you practically all of the gains of
writing extensions but not the headache. Pyrex is a new language created
specifically for writing Python extensions. It is a hybrid of C and Python,
leaning much more toward Python: in fact, the Pyrex Web site goes as far as
saying that, “Pyrex is Python with C data types.” You only need to write code
in the Pyrex syntax and run the Pyrex compiler on the source. Pyrex creates C
files, which can then be compiled and used as a normal extension would. Some
have sworn off C programming forever upon discovering Pyrex. You can get Pyrex
at its home page:
创建C/C++扩展的一个很明显的坏处是你必须要写C/C++代码。你能利用它们的优点，但
更重要的是，你也会碰到它们的缺点。Pyrex可以让你只取扩展的优点，而完全没有后顾
之忧。它是一种更偏向Python的C语言和Python语言的混合语言。事实上，Pyrex的官方网站上就
说“Pyrex是具有C数据类型的Python“。你只要用Pyrex的语法写代码，然后运行Pyrex编译
器去编译源代码。Pyrex会生成相应的C代码，这些代码可以被编译成普通的扩展。你可
以在它的官方网站下载到Pyrex：

http://cosc.canterbury.ac.nz/~greg/python/Pyrex


Psyco

Pyrex gives us the advantage that you no longer have to write pure C; however,
do you need to learn its syntax, “yet another language.” In the end, your Pyrex
code turns into C anyway. You use C/C++, C/C++ with SWIG, or Pyrex because you
still want that performance boost you are looking for. What if you can obtain
performance gains without changing your Python code?
Pyrex免去了我们再去写纯C代码的麻烦。不过，你要去学会它的那一套与众不同的语法。
最后，你的Pyrex代码还是会被转成C的代码。无论你用C/C++，C/C++加上SWIG，还是Pyrex，
都是因为你想要加快你的程序的速度。如果你可以在不改动你的Python代码的同时，又能
获得速度的提升，那该多好啊。

Psyco’s concept is quite different from those other approaches. Rather than
writing C code, why not just make your existing Python code run faster?
Psyco的理念与其它的方法截然不同。与其改成C的代码，为何不让你已有的Python代码
运行的更快一些呢？

Psyco serves as a just-in-time (JIT) compiler so you do not have to change to
your source other than importing the Psyco module and telling it to start
optimizing your code (during runtime).
Psyco是一个just-in-time(JIT)编译器，它能在运行时自动把字节码转为本地代码运行。
所以，你只要（在运行时）导入Psyco模块，然后告诉它要开始优化代码就可以了。而
不用修改自己的代码。

Psyco can also profile your code to see where it can make the most signifi-
cant improvements. You can even enable logging to see what Psyco does while
optimizing your code. For more information, go to its main Web site:
Psyco也可以检查你代码各个部分的运行时间，以找出瓶颈所在。你甚至可以打开日志
功能，来查看Psyco在优化你的代码的时候，都做了些什么。你可以访问以下网站获取
更多的信息：

http://psyco.sf.net


Embedding
嵌入

Embedding is another feature available in Python. It is the inverse of an
extension. Rather than taking C code and wrapping it into Python, you take a C
application and wrap a Python interpreter inside it. This has the effect of
giving a potentially large, monolithic, and perhaps rigid, proprietary, and/or
mission-critical application the power of having an embedded Python inter-
preter. Once you have Python, well, it’s like a whole new ball game.
嵌入是Python的另一功能。与把C代码包装到Python中的扩展相对的，嵌入是把Python解释
器包装到C的程序中。这样做可以给大型的，单一的，要求严格的，私有的并且（或者）
极其重要的应用程序内嵌Python解释器的能力。一旦内嵌了Python，世界完全不一样了。

For extension writer, there is a set of official docs that you should refer to
for additional information.
Python提供了很多官方文档供写扩展的人参考。

Here are links to some of the Python documentation related to this chapter’s
topics:
下面是一些与本章相关的Python文档：

Extending and Embedding
扩展与嵌入

http://docs.python.org/ext

Python/C API

http://docs.python.org/api

Distributing Python Modules
分发Python模块

http://docs.python.org/dist


22.4  Exercises
练习

22–1. Extending Python. What are some of the advantages of Python extensions?
22-1. 扩展Python. 编写Python扩展都有些什么好处？

22–2. Extending Python. Can you see any disadvantages or dangers of using
extensions?
22-2. 扩展Python. 编写Python扩展都有些什么不好的地方或是危险的地方？

22–3. Writing Extensions. Obtain or find a C/C++ compiler and write a small
program with it to (re)familiarize yourself with C/C++ programming. Find your
Python distribution directory and locate the Misc/Makefile.pre.in file. Take
the program you just wrote and wrap it in Python. Go through the steps
necessary to create a shared object. Access that module from Python and test
it.
22-3. 编写扩展. 下载或找到一个C/C++编译器，并写一个小程序(重新)熟悉一下C/C++
编程。找到你的Python所在的目录，并找到Misc/Makefile.pre.in文件。把你刚写的
程序包装到Python当中。按步骤把你的模块编译成动态库，从Python中调用你的模块并
测试一下是否正确。

22–4. Porting from Python to C. Take several of the exercises you did in
earlier chapters and port them to C/C++ as extension modules.
22-4. 把Python移植到C。选几个你在前几章写的代码，并把它们做为模块移植到C/C++
中。

22–5. Wrapping C Code. Find a piece of C/C++ code, which you may have done a
long time ago, but want to port to Python. Instead of porting, make it an
extension module.
22-5. 包装C代码。找一段你之前写的，想移植到Python的C/C++代码。不要去移植，
把这段代码改成扩展模块。

22–6. Writing Extensions. In Exercise 13–3, you created a dollarize() function
as part of a class to convert a floating point value to a financial numeric
string with embedded dollar signs and commas. Create an extension featuring a
wrapped dollarize() function and integrate a regression testing function, i.e.,
test(), into the module. Extra credit: In addition to creating a C extension,
also rewrite dollarize() in Pyrex.
22-6. 编写扩展。在13-3的练习中，你写了一个dollarize()函数，它能把浮点数转为
前置美元符号，逗号分隔的货币金额字符串。请创建一个扩展，包装dollarize()函数，
并在模块中增加一个回归测试函数test()。附加题：除了创建C扩展外，再用Pyrex重写
dollarize()函数。

22–7. Extending versus Embedding. What is the difference between extending
and embedding?
22-7. 扩展和嵌入。扩展和嵌入的区别是什么？

